Finding Aid for the Walter Gabrielson papers LSC.1830
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 3. Artwork, ca. 1975-2008
  - Baseball -- fielding visual reference, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Baseball -- second base visual reference, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Baseball -- baseball parks visual reference, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Includes photographs of Gabrielson and Goldberg at Dodger stadium
  - Baseball -- Cubist style sketches, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Cats -- art deco cats -- drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Cats -- art deco cats -- drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Cats -- art deco cats -- preliminary drawings for completed works, ca. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Cats -- cat's paw project, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- draft sketches (folder 1 of 3), ca. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Includes gouache sketches
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- draft sketches (folder 2 of 3), ca. 2001 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- draft sketches (folder 3 of 3), ca. 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- notebook: record of writings, ca. 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Consists of notes on phrases to use in Chloe sez project
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- notebook: notes, ca. 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- notebook: formatting guides, ca. 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- notebook: Oscar Wilde quotes for drawings, ca. 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- color copies, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- black and white copies (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- black and white copies (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- black and white copies (folder 3 of 4), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- black and white copies (folder 4 of 4), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- copies of works given away, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- journal of progress on project, 1997-2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    From front of notebook contains notes on Chloe Sez project and from the back of the notebook writings labeled "A Piano Journal"
  - Cats -- Chloe sez -- biographical materials, ca. 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Cats -- Clyde comic strip -- text preparation, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cats -- Clyde comic strip -- drawings, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Cats -- pencil drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Cats -- pencil drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Includes set of black and white photocopies of Clyde comic strip
  - Cats -- studies of sleeping cats, 2000-2005 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cats -- collected sketches and source material (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Cats -- collected sketches and source material (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Cats -- sketches, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Cubism and futurism art historical reference, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Cubism and futurism -- sketches of people (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Cubism and futurism -- sketches of people (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Cubism and futurism -- sketches, ca. 1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Deadly Sins -- preparatory drawings, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Del Coronado Series -- photographic studies and drawings, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Donut shop -- preparatory work and visual reference, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Double bills -- visual reference (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Double bills -- visual reference (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Dramas -- preliminary drawings for paintings, ca. 2008 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Dramas -- preliminary drawings for paintings, ca. 2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Dramas -- drawings and visual reference, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Dramas -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2004 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Dramas -- drawings and visual reference, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Dramas -- preparatory drawings, ca. 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Dramas -- preparatory drawings and visual reference, ca. 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Dramas -- preliminary drawings for paintings, ca. 2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Dramas -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1998 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Dramas -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1998 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dramas -- first dates-drawings and visual reference, ca. 2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Dramas -- romantic -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2001 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Ed Wortz -- drawings, ca. 2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Drawings are predominantly images of Buddha
  - Ed Wortz-- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - England -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Europe -- drawings, ca. 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Europe -- preparatory drawings and photographs, ca. 1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Includes photographs of Nancy Goldberg and their trip to Europe
  - Faces -- preliminary drawings for completed works, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Faces -- visual reference for paintings, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Faces -- style -- visual reference materials, 2003-2006 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Faces -- style -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Faces -- studies (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2007 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Faces -- studies (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2007 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Faces -- visual reference (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Faces -- visual reference (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Faces -- studies of Gabrielson"s friends (folder 1 of 4), ca. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Includes photographs and drawings of friends and acquaintances
  - Faces -- studies of Gabrielson"s friends (folder 2 of 4), ca. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Faces -- studies of Gabrielson"s friends (folder 3 of 4), ca. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Faces -- studies of Gabrielson"s friends (folder 4 of 4), ca. 2004 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Faces -- preparatory drawings and visual reference, ca. 2008 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Includes oil sketch
  - Faces -- drawings and visual reference, Ca. 2008 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Faces -- preparatory drawings for completed works (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Faces -- preparatory drawings for completed works (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Faces -- hands and faces -- studies, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Faces -- studies, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Includes copies of drawings and images of a man"s face
  - Faces -- black and white photocopies, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Series of numbered photocopied drawings of faces
  - Farm workers piece -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Flowers -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Includes lists of numbered slides corresponding to Gabrielson"s numbering system as well as correspondence with Next Monet online gallery
  - Flowers -- preparatory work for completed paintings (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Flowers -- preparatory work for completed paintings (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Flowers -- visual reference materials (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Flowers -- visual reference materials (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Flowers -- visual reference materials (folder 3 of 4), undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Flowers -- visual reference materials (folder 4 of 4), undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Flowers -- cactus -- preparatory drawings for completed works, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Flowers -- cactus -- preparatory drawings for completed works, ca. 2004 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Flowers -- cactus -- visual reference and preparatory drawings (folders 1 of 2), ca. 2004 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Includes large amounts of copy photography
  - Flowers -- cactus -- visual reference and preparatory drawings (folders 2 of 2), ca. 2004 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Flowers -- roses -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Flowers -- roses -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Consists of photographic and drawn studies
  - Food -- preparatory materials for completed works (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Food - preparatory materials for completed works (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Food -- visual reference materials for paintings, ca. 2007 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Food -- preliminary drawings and visual reference, ca. 2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Food -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 3), 2005-2008 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Food -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 3), 2005-2008 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Food -- drawings and visual reference (folder 3 of 3), ca. 2008 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Food -- visual reference for paintings, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Food -- line drawings, ca. 2002 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Includes finished pen and ink drawing
  - Food -- visual style reference, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Food -- breakfast -- drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Food -- pies-- drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Food -- plateful -- drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Food -- still life -- drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Food -- miscellaneous drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    File originally labeled "to file" by Gabrielson
  - Food -- miscellaneous drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Food -- miscellaneous drawings and visual reference (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Forever Young -- comic series, ca. 1995 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Portions of this folder are in the oversize box 85, folders 2 and 3.
  - Golden West Hotel -- photographic studies and drawings, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Goodbys from [sic] -- preparatory drawings (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    'Goodbys from' series focuses tragic deaths of famous creative personalities.
  - Goodbys from [sic] -- preparatory drawings (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Goodbys from [sic] -- preparatory drawings (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Goodbys from [sic] -- typographical studies, ca. 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Hawaii notebook: ephemera, 1979-1990 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Hawaii notebook: photographs of buildings (folder 1 of 2), 1979-1990 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Hawaii notebook: photographs of buildings (folder 2 of 2), 1979-1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Hawaii notebook: drawings of store fronts, 1979-1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Hawaii notebook: photographs of buildings, 1979-1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Homage series -- reference materials and photographic records, 1998-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Horizontal narrative -- preliminary drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Horizontal narrative -- preparatory drawings and visual reference, ca. 1991 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Humanist -- one person -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Humanist -- two people -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Humanist -- two people -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Humanist -- two people -- visual reference and drawings (folder 3 of 4), undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Humanist -- two people -- visual reference and drawings (folder 4 of 4), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Humanist -- three people -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Humanist -- drawings not developed, ca. 1984 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Humanist -- search for meaning [sic], undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Jargon -- drawings and reference (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Jargon -- drawings and reference (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Jargon -- notes and sketches, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Consists of source material, notes, and sketches about types of jargon, particularly in the art field
  - Jury series -- preparatory materials, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Kachinas -- sketches for completed paintings, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Kachinas -- drawings, ca. 1989-1995 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: sculpture patterns (folder 1 of 4), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: sculpture patterns (folder 2 of 4), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: sculpture patterns (folder 3 of 4), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: sculpture patterns (folder 4 of 4), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: preparatory drawings for sculptures (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: preparatory drawings for sculptures (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Kachinas -- notebook: preparatory drawings for sculptures (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Kachinas -- drawings for sculptures, ca. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Kachinas -- paintings -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2006 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Kachinas -- paintings -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2006 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Kachinas possibilities [sic] -- source material and drawings (folder 1 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Kachinas possibilities [sic] -- source material and drawings (folder 2 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Kachinas possibilities [sic] -- source material and drawings (folder 3 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Kachinas possibilities [sic] -- source material and drawings (folder 4 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Kachinas -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Kachinas -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Landscape -- visual reference for works to be developed, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Landscape -- preparatory drawings for completed works (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2005 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Landscape -- preparatory drawings for completed works (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2005 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Landscape -- drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Landscape -- drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Landscape -- preparatory drawings for paintings, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Includes progress chart for several paintings
  - Landscape -- visual reference, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Landscape -- visual reference and drawings, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Includes photographs of Hawaii
  - Landscape -- visual reference for completed works, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Landscape -- stylistic reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Landscape -- stylistic reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2004 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Landscape -- birches -- source material and drawings (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Landscape -- birches -- source material and drawings (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Landscape -- birches -- source material and drawings (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Landscape -- cloud construction visual reference and drawings, ca. 2002 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Landscape -- clouds -- visual reference, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Landscape -- clouds -- visual reference and drawings, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Landscape -- clouds -- visual reference and drawings for future works, ca. 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Landscape -- clouds -- preparatory drawings for completed works, ca. 2003 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Landscape -- eucalyptus trees -- photographic studies and drawings, ca. 2002 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Landscape -- Jalama beach -- studies, ca. 2002 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Landscape -- order -- studies and visual reference, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Landscape -- panoramic paintings -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Landscape -- rivers -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Landscape -- skies -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Landscape -- western (U.S.) -- visual reference and drawings, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Landscape -- total green [sic], ca. 2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Consists of lists of paintings from different series as well as drawings of flowers
  - Lawyer art -- business materials, 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence about creating a website
  - Lawyer art -- preliminary drawings and notes, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lawyer art -- preparatory drawings (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Lawyer art -- preparatory drawings (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Includes gouache sketch
  - Lawyer art -- gouache sketches, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Lawyer art -- notebook: first set, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Consists predominantly of color copies of gouache pieces as a type of catalog
  - Lawyer art -- notebook: second set, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Lawyer art -- notebook: third set, ca. 2003 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Lawyer art -- courtroom drawings, 1983-2004 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Man in brown series -- sketches and visual reference, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Mask as metaphor -- visual reference and drawings, ca. 1980 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Movie sculptures - drawings and source material, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Music -- in progress (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1998 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Music -- in progress (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1998 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - People -- drawings (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - People -- drawings (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - People -- drawings (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - People -- visual reference for paintings (folder 1 of 2), 2008 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - People -- visual reference for paintings (folder 2 of 2), 2008 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - People -- visual reference and preparatory sketches, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - People -- people, average [sic] -- visual reference and drawings, ca. 2007 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - People -- preliminary drawings for works in progress, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - People -- new source material and drawings, ca. 2003 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - People -- multiple people interacting -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - People -- at desks -- drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - People -- begging child -- preparatory drawings, ca. 2003 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - People -- nudes -- drawings, ca. 2001 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - People -- portraits -- drawings and visual reference for completed works, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - People -- portraits -- notes, ca. 2006 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - People -- women -- drawings for small works, ca. 1995 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - People -- women"s faces -- visual reference as possible works, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Consists of visual reference and preparatory drawings collected for possible paintings
  - Poker faces -- notebook: notes and sketches, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Poker faces -- notebook: glossaries of poker terms, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Poker faces -- notebook: drawings and color copies, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Poker faces -- notebook: preparatory sketches, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Poker faces -- notebook: color copies of finished works, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Poker faces -- notebook: instructions for silkscreening, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Poker faces -- preparatory sketches, ca. 2004 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Railroad -- preparatory drawings for completed works, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Railroad -- drawings selected for paintings, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Railroad -- visual reference and preparatory drawings, ca. 1986 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Railroad -- drawings and source material, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Railroad -- drawings selected for development, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Railroad -- visual reference for new works (folder 1 of 3), 2008 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Railroad -- visual reference for new works (folder 2 of 3), 2008 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Railroad -- visual reference for new works (folder 3 of 3), 2008 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Railroad -- preparatory drawings to develop (folder 1 of 2), 2008 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Railroad -- preparatory drawings to develop (folder 2 of 2), 2008 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Railroad -- notebook one: notes, ca. 2008 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Railroad -- notebook one: railroad art, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Railroad -- notebook one: to do, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes visual reference as source material for works
  - Railroad -- notebook one: people, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: bridges, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: stations, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: railroad cars, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: modern, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: engines (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Railroad -- notebook two: engines (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Railroad -- notebook three: smoke, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Railroad -- notebook three: trains, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Railroad -- notebook three: train perspective, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Railroad -- notebook three: rear and side views of trains, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Railroad -- notebook four: glossary of rail terms, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Railroad -- notebook four: sets, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Railroad -- notebook four: platform cars, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Railroad -- notebook four: yard, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Railroad -- notebook four: cabooses, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Includes a drawing and some photographs
  - Railroad -- trains drawings and visual reference, ca. 2002 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Railroad -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2008 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Religion -- Religious art project (folder 1 of 2), 1996 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Craig Svare about commissions from Lutheran community
  - Religion -- Religious art project (folder 2 of 2), 1996 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Religion -- Jesus piece, ca. 1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Religion -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Includes drawings of different religious costumes
  - Religion -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Saint Joseph"s Medical Center paintings, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence with a hospital representative concerning a donation of Gabrielson"s work from Hilton Burbank to St. Joseph"s
  - Scenes -- preliminary work for paintings, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Scenes -- preparatory drawings for paintings not completed, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Scenes -- drawings and visual reference for abandoned works, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings to consider (folder 1 of 5), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings to consider (folder 2 of 5), undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings to consider (folder 3 of 5), undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings to consider (folder 4 of 5), undated (Box 21, Folder 15)